<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Playing with data</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Playing with data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday To Me!</title>
      <link>/2018/01/happy-birthday-to-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/happy-birthday-to-me/</guid>
      <description>Happy Birthday To Me! Today is my birthday. To celebrate I decided to look at what was in the news on January 27 every year since I was born. Mainly I want to see if the news were positive or negative.
 Getting the data I start buy creating a list of dates. I feel like there is probably a more straightforward way of doing this but I am currently obsessed with map so this is how I did it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please like me</title>
      <link>/2018/01/please-like-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/please-like-me/</guid>
      <description>Sundays When I woke up this morning I wrote a long to do list. Instead of working through the list I somehow ended up spending most of my day playing in R.
 Scraping the web I have been keen to try web scraping in R for a while so I gave rvest a go. I was a bit too restless to actually read any tutorials so I just started trying different commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regressions using completly fake data!</title>
      <link>/2018/01/fake-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/fake-data/</guid>
      <description>Why can’t I just have all of the data? I have been updating some code that uses data that I don’t have access to. I used one of the data sets from the survival package but it annoyed me that the variable names were not what I wanted them to be and I couldn’t be bothered changing them. I was killing time on a train the other day and discovered the simstudy package and decided to give it a go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a map (or my first blogpost)</title>
      <link>/2018/01/maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/maps/</guid>
      <description>Getting the data A couple of months ago I discovered a package developed by Public Health England that makes it easier to extract the data behind their fingertips website (https://fingertips.phe.org.uk/). I wanted to try it and as I like maps I decided to download some data at CCG level and make an interactive choropleth map using the leaflet package. I use select_indicators to browse the indicators and pick one at random that seems to have CCG level data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>