<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Playing with data</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Playing with data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Used Code</title>
      <link>/2019/01/frequently-used-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/frequently-used-code/</guid>
      <description>Motivation There are some things that I always forget how to do in R. I have decided to add some of those code snippets to this blog so I that I can look them up when I need them.
Droping variables using a vector of names I often have a pre-specified vector of variables names that I use frequently and sometimes I want to drop those variables. The trick is to use one_of around the vector with variable names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settlers of Catan - the random generator</title>
      <link>/2018/09/settlers-of-catan-the-random-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/settlers-of-catan-the-random-generator/</guid>
      <description>Background Back in March I wrote a blog post about my favourite board game Settlers of Catan. The code generates a random catan board but there is no interactivity for when you want to create a different random board. You can read it in its entirety here and somewhere in that post I promised to actually create an app so you can create your own board. I tried when I wrote the original blog post but I struggled with Shiny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first hackathon (part 2)</title>
      <link>/2018/07/my-first-hackathon-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/my-first-hackathon-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Gender pay gap hackathon (part 2) This is part 2 of my blog about the gender pay gap hack that I went to. You can read part 1 here.
 Reflections It has taken me a long time to write the second part of my experience of the hackathon. I think this is partly because I was unsure how/whether to show the dashboard. This was my first attempt at a shiny dashboard and I did not focus on picking the best metrics for the graphs so I don’t feel like I am showing anything useful and I don’t like the thought of sharing graphs that I am not sure are displaying the data in an appropriate way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first hackathon (part 1)</title>
      <link>/2018/06/my-first-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/my-first-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>Gender pay gap hackathon Last weekend I went to my first hackathon. It was organised by the AI club for gender minorities, codebar and ellpha. We used data on the gender pay gap available here. I had a great time so I wanted to share my experience. This is the first part of my first hackathon.
 The deep dive team There were different tables with different themes and I picked deep dive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first tidy Tuesday</title>
      <link>/2018/05/my-first-tidy-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/my-first-tidy-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>Tidy Tuesday I have seen some cool graphs on twitter created for Tidy Tuesday. I wanted to join in on the fun so I downloaded the data from week 3 and started playinh. The data are from our world in data and I downloaded the data file from github.
mortality &amp;lt;- readxl::read_excel(here::here(&amp;quot;global_mortality.xlsx&amp;quot;)) glimpse(mortality) ## Observations: 6,156 ## Variables: 35 ## $ country &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Afghanistan&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Afg... ## $ country_code &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;quot;AFG&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;AFG&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;AFG&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settlers of Catan</title>
      <link>/2018/03/settlers-of-catan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/settlers-of-catan/</guid>
      <description>Settlers of catan In our living room there is an old chest hiding some real treasures. Every now and again we will get Settlers of Catan out. I never grow tired of playing it as the board changes every time. The game has 19 hexagon shaped tiles that are placed at random. Eighteen tiles are linked to different resources -wheat, rock, wood, sheep and clay- and the 19th is the desert where the much feared robber lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My trip to Mexico in emojis</title>
      <link>/2018/03/mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/mexico/</guid>
      <description>The code that never really worked This post is the result of hours and hours of me trying to write some code but never getting it quite right. I think that one of the worst things that you can do to yourself is to be scared to admit that you are struggling because you will end up never trying anything new. That is why I am publishing what I have got so far despite not being very happy with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should I have for lunch?</title>
      <link>/2018/02/what-should-i-have-for-lunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/what-should-i-have-for-lunch/</guid>
      <description>Inspiration I was having lunch with some colleagues the other day when they told me about a restaurant spreadsheet that they used to use to randomly pick a place to get lunch from. I of course felt the need to see if I could create something similar in R.
I had also seen a really cool blog post using the osmdata package to look at the number of pubs close to metro stations in Paris.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday To Me!</title>
      <link>/2018/01/happy-birthday-to-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/happy-birthday-to-me/</guid>
      <description>Happy Birthday To Me! Today is my birthday. To celebrate I decided to look at what was in the news on January 27 every year since I was born. Mainly I want to see if the news were positive or negative.
 Getting the data I start buy creating a list of dates. I feel like there is probably a more straightforward way of doing this but I am currently obsessed with map so this is how I did it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please like me</title>
      <link>/2018/01/please-like-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/please-like-me/</guid>
      <description>Sundays When I woke up this morning I wrote a long to do list. Instead of working through the list I somehow ended up spending most of my day playing in R.
 Scraping the web I have been keen to try web scraping in R for a while so I gave rvest a go. I was a bit too restless to actually read any tutorials so I just started trying different commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regressions using completly fake data!</title>
      <link>/2018/01/fake-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/fake-data/</guid>
      <description>Why can’t I just have all of the data? I have been updating some code that uses data that I don’t have access to. I used one of the data sets from the survival package but it annoyed me that the variable names were not what I wanted them to be and I couldn’t be bothered changing them. I was killing time on a train the other day and discovered the simstudy package and decided to give it a go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a map (or my first blogpost)</title>
      <link>/2018/01/maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/maps/</guid>
      <description>Getting the data A couple of months ago I discovered a package developed by Public Health England that makes it easier to extract the data behind their fingertips website (https://fingertips.phe.org.uk/). I wanted to try it and as I like maps I decided to download some data at CCG level and make an interactive choropleth map using the leaflet package. I use select_indicators to browse the indicators and pick one at random that seems to have CCG level data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>