<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Playing with data</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Playing with data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Maps</title>
      <link>/2018/01/maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/maps/</guid>
      <description>Getting the data A couple of months ago I discovered a package developed by Public Health England that makes it easier to extract the data behind their [fingertips website] (fingertips.phe.gov.uk). I like maps so I decided to download some data at CCG level and make an interactive choropleth map using the leaflet package. I use select_indicators to browse the indicators and pick one at random that seems to have CCG level data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to Mexico</title>
      <link>/2017/12/going-to-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/going-to-mexico/</guid>
      <description>In February next year I am going to Mexico with a group of friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bestest dog</title>
      <link>/2017/12/the-bestest-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/the-bestest-dog/</guid>
      <description>Who is the bestest dog? After calling my parents’ dog the bestest dog of all I wanted to find out who the internet thought was the bestest dog. “We rate dogs” on twitter was the obvious choice as the almighty judge of all dogs.
I started by pulling all tweets by @rate_dogs using the twitteR and ROAuth packages. I decide to not include retweets or replies as I only cared about the official opinion of @rate_dogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying something new</title>
      <link>/2017/12/trying-something-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/trying-something-new/</guid>
      <description>I write a lot of short snippets of code that that end up in a folder on my computer (often half-finished) never to been seen by anyone. I decided to make</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>