<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>magick on Playing with data</title>
    <link>/tags/magick/</link>
    <description>Recent content in magick on Playing with data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/magick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy EasteR</title>
      <link>/2020/04/happy-easter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/happy-easter/</guid>
      <description>Background I decided to send personalised Easter cards this year. The plan was to dig out photos of friend and make them more eastery. I found a lovely frame to add to the photos only to realise that I had no idea how to combine them. A quick internet search left me annoyed, so I decided to do what I always do. I turned to R!
 Getting to work I used the magick package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settlers of Catan - the random generator</title>
      <link>/2018/09/settlers-of-catan-the-random-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/settlers-of-catan-the-random-generator/</guid>
      <description>Background Back in March I wrote a blog post about my favourite board game Settlers of Catan. The code generates a random catan board but there is no interactivity for when you want to create a different random board. You can read it in its entirety here and somewhere in that post I promised to actually create an app so you can create your own board. I tried when I wrote the original blog post but I struggled with Shiny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settlers of Catan</title>
      <link>/2018/03/settlers-of-catan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/settlers-of-catan/</guid>
      <description>Settlers of catan In our living room there is an old chest hiding some real treasures. Every now and again we will get Settlers of Catan out. I never grow tired of playing it as the board changes every time. The game has 19 hexagon shaped tiles that are placed at random. Eighteen tiles are linked to different resources -wheat, rock, wood, sheep and clay- and the 19th is the desert where the much feared robber lives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>